tremorvideo.com 2018-11-09

# Privacy Policy

Introduction

This privacy policy describes the types of information that Tremor Video DSP, Inc., a Taptica Company, (“we” or “Tremor Video DSP”), collects on our corporate website and through our video advertising services. It also describes how that information is used and the choices we offer to users, or you, about the collection and use of such information.

### PRIVACY POLICY FOR TREMOR VIDEO DSP SERVICES

### Effective Date: June 22, 2018

What does Tremor Video DSP do?

Tremor Video DSP, Inc., a Taptica Company, is an online video advertising software company. Tremor Video DSP’s advertiser customers engage us to display their video ads in streaming content that is featured on websites and applications across the Internet, including content that is viewable on mobile devices, tablets and TVs. Sellers of advertisements utilize our solutions to improve their yield and maximize the value of their video advertising inventory.

How does Tremor Video DSP’s software select the video ads that I see?

Tremor Video DSP’s proprietary ad serving software displays video ads, typically immediately before or during the streaming of featured content on a website or application. The video ad is provided to Tremor Video DSP by an advertiser, and the featured advertising content is shown on the websites and applications of a content provider.

Our advertisers may specify where, when, and in what context they want their video ads to be displayed. These specifications are sometimes called targeting parameters.

Tremor Video DSP uses its proprietary ad serving software to target, select and deliver ads according to the advertisers’ specifications. In order to optimize the delivery of a video ad, Tremor Video DSP’s software collects and analyzes information provided by the website or application publisher, information collected from a website or application user’s computer or device, and information provided by the advertiser, among other sources, which, in turn, is automatically recorded (logged) by the Tremor Video DSP servers. Examples of the types of information we may collect and store in the server logs include: browser type and language, operating system, Internet Protocol address (for example, to identify a user’s general location), page URL and referral URL (the URL that led you to the page featuring our software), website content (e.g., pictures or ads on the website), video player size, video content (such as video title, description, category), how a user interacts with a video (such as how often they start or stop a video), date and time of request, internet service provider, advertising cookies stored on a user’s device. Our advertising partners may also provide us with audience segment data, which is a non-identifiable list of users that our advertising partners believe to be interested in a certain topic or product or are within demographic categories the advertiser would like to reach. When selecting, targeting and delivering ads, Tremor Video DSP does not actively collect, and does not use or store information such as names, email addresses, or contact information that can be used to readily identify an individual. 

Tremor Video DSP’s ad serving software may use cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies to select, target, and measure the effectiveness of the advertisements we serve. We use these technologies to help determine what ads to present so that they may best relate to the possible preferences and interests of users based on information collected across multiple websites that they visit. We call this practice of collecting data about a user’s online activities to deliver advertising targeted to a user’s likely interests “interest-based advertising.”

A “cookie” is generally a small text file that is sent to a user’s computer. Cookies are commonly assigned by online services, such as websites or ad technologies, to recognize a computer or device that they have encountered before. A cookie is associated with a specific site domain, a specific computer, and a specific Internet browser program. Our advertising cookies are not used to gather the user’s name, street address, e-mail address, or telephone number(s).

A “web beacon” is a small piece of code placed on web pages that can be used, among other things, to count the users who visit the web page, or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a user viewing that page.

How does Tremor Video DSP deliver ads to mobile applications?

In the case of advertisements targeted, selected, and delivered to mobile applications, for example, apps on a smartphone, the Tremor Video DSP software collects information provided by the user’s mobile device, including certain unique mobile operating system advertising IDs, such as Apple’s Identifier for Advertising ID (IDFA) or Google’s Android Advertising ID (AAID) to target, select, and deliver advertisements. Other examples of information we may collect to target, select and deliver advertisements may be the type of the mobile device, the device’s IP address, what apps installed on the device are using the Tremor Video DSP services, how the app user interacts with videos within an app using the Tremor Video DSP services, and the location of a mobile device if a user enables collection of location data for the app using Tremor Video DSP services through the available features on that mobile device. 

How does Tremor Video DSP recognize a user across multiple devices? 

Tremor Video DSP’s software may, in some cases, be able to infer within a reasonable probability that a particular computer or device may be correlated with the same Tremor Video DSP identifier (e.g., cookie, advertising IDs, IP address) that we have previously associated to another computer or device. In such cases, Tremor Video DSP’s software may be able to infer that a device (e.g _._ a computer) and another device (e.g. a smartphone) are used by the same user. Where such an inference can be made, we may use this information to target, select and deliver ads across multiple computers and devices. This is sometimes referred to as cross-device advertising.

What are examples of ad choices Tremor Video DSP offers to users?

  * Opt out of Tremor Video DSP’s cookie used for interest-based advertising by clicking on the “Opt Out” button at the top of this page. Your web browser will need to accept cookies for the opt-out to be effective.
  * Follow the opt out link in the AdChoices Icon featured on the advertisements served by Tremor Video DSP.
  * Opt out of cookies used for interest-based advertising by a number of online advertising companies at the [Digital Advertising Alliance Consumer Opt-Out Page for Online Behavioral Advertising](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/).
  * Manage the settings on your smartphone. Find out how you may opt of mobile application interest - based advertising at the Mobile App Opt - Out Guide for more information. Please be aware that your smartphone may not offer the same features.
  * Set your browser to reject cookies, and remove the cookies that have already been placed. Find out how at [All About Cookies](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) for more information.

Four things to know about opting out:

  * You will still see video ads from Tremor Video DSP after you opt out. However, the ads that you see will be less relevant to you.
  * You will need to opt out separately for each browser and each device. There is not a single opt out that governs all your browsers and devices.
  * If you change your browser or device, you will need to opt out again for each new browser and device. The new browser and device does not inherit your prior settings.
  * If you delete the opt out cookie from your browser, you will need to opt out again from that browser.

Do the Tremor Video DSP services respond to browser Do-Not-Track signals?

Our services do not respond to browser Do Not Track signals. To opt out of Tremor Video DSP’s cookie used for interest-based advertising by clicking on the “Opt Out” button at the top of this page. For more information about Do Not Track signals, please visit www.allaboutdnt.com.

How do we use third-party service providers?

Tremor Video DSP and its advertisers may use third-party ad service providers to help deliver advertisements. These ad service providers use cookies, web beacons, or other technologies to select, target, deliver, and measure the effectiveness of advertisements, including when determining what ads to present so that they may best relate to the possible preferences and interests of users. Tremor Video DSP may use data that ad service providers collect in the delivery of interest-based advertisements.

Tremor Video DSP may share non-personally identifiable information about users gathered by means of cookies, web beacons, or other technologies, including anonymous identifiers used in connection with mobile applications, with certain ad service providers so that they can help Tremor Video DSP deliver more relevant advertisements, including for cross - device advertising. The use of cookies, web beacons, or other technologies by other ad service providers is subject to their respective privacy policies, and not by the privacy policy of Tremor Video DSP. You can find out more about ad service providers and the choices you have about their technologies by clicking on the links at the bottom of this privacy policy. Similarly, the publishers (such as websites and mobile applications) to which we deliver an ad are subject to their own privacy policies and not the privacy policy of Tremor Video DSP.

Is information transferred to Tremor Video DSP and affiliates?

Tremor Video DSP may transfer or assign the information it collects in connection with its business to any successor-in-interest to Tremor Video DSP (such as a company that acquires Tremor Video DSP), or internally to one or more affiliates (such as a corporate subsidiary, an affiliate company, or parent). Tremor Video DSP may also disclose information if it determines that an applicable law, regulation, or legal process requires it, or if Tremor Video DSP determines that it needs to share such information to protect or enforce Tremor Video DSP’s rights or the rights of our customers or another user.

Security

We have taken steps to help protect the information we collect through Tremor Video DSP’s advertising services from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. We take measures to protect information we share with third parties. However, no data security measures can guarantee security.

### PRIVACY POLICY FOR THE TREMOR VIDEO DSP CORPORATE WEBSITE 

### Effective Date: June 22, 2018

[www.tremorvideodsp.com](http://tremorvideodsp.com/index.html) is the corporate website of Tremor Video DSP, Inc., a Taptica Company. This website (the “Tremor Video DSP Site” or “Site”) provides users, typically current and prospective customers, partners, and job seekers, with information about our products and services, and gives users the opportunity to contact us for further information.

This privacy policy describes the types of information that Tremor Video DSP collects on the Site and how that information is used. Tremor Video DSP reserves the right to revise this privacy policy from time to time by posting the changes on the Site. Your continued use of the Site constitutes your acceptance of the current posted privacy policy. If you have questions about this privacy policy, please email us at [privacy@tremorvideodsp.com](mailto:PRIVACY@TREMORVIDEODSP.COM). To learn about how we use information collected through the Tremor Video DSP services or to opt-out of the delivery of interest-based advertising delivered through the Tremor Video DSP services, please see the Privacy Policy for Tremor Video DSP Services below.

What information does the Tremor Video DSP Site collect?

_Personally  identifiable information_  
Personally identifiable information is information that identifies a user as a specific individual, such as a name, email address, mailing address, or phone number, or data that you provide that Tremor Video DSP can reasonably link to other information that you provide in order to personally identify you.

The Tremor Video DSP Site collects personally identifiable information about users only if a user voluntarily provides that information to the Site. Personally identifiable information is collected on the Tremor Video DSP Site in various instances including, without limitation:

  * _Information requests._ A Site user, typically a current or prospective customer, partner, or job seeker, submits an inquiry to the Site using the “Contact Us”, “Request a Demo” and “sign me up” functions, and provides his or her name, address, email address, and/or telephone number so that Tremor Video DSP is able to respond.
  * _Comment on  news, blog, or other posting._A user posts a comment in the blog or news section of the Site, and submits his or her name and email address with the post.
  * _Subscribe to email newsletter._ To subscribe to the Tremor Video DSP email newsletter, a user provides his or her name, email address, and other contact information. Each newsletter will provide the user with the option of unsubscribing from future newsletters.
  * _Subscription feed._ A user subscribes to the Site’s subscription function by providing his or her email address.
  * _Access to Tremor Video DSP web-based client interface_. A current Tremor Video DSP client accesses the client/customer-only areas of the Site by submitting his or her username and password.
  * _Request for feedback._ From time to time, the Tremor Video DSP Site may ask users for voluntary feedback that will help us improve the Site. In connection with such feedback, a user may choose to provide optional name and contact information.
  * _Promotions, sweepstakes, or contests.  _From time to time, Tremor Video DSP may sponsor or co-sponsor promotions, sweepstakes or contests, in response to which a user may provide information, such as his or her name, email address, or other contact information, and/or to answer certain questions on an entry form.

_Non-personally identifiable information_

Non-personally identifiable information includes demographic information (such as age, gender, city, or state) and a user’s clickstream information. The Tremor Video DSP Site collects information about users and stores it in log files. This information includes non-personally identifiable information that your browser automatically sends whenever you visit this Site, including information about your web request, your browser type, browser language, date, and time of the request.

How does Tremor Video DSP use information collected by the Tremor Video DSP Site?

_Personally  identifiable information_  
Tremor Video DSP uses the personally identifiable information you provide:

  * To respond to your inquiries and requests, and to keep accurate records concerning the services you are requesting through the Tremor Video DSP Site.
  * For marketing the Tremor Video DSP services. For example, we may use information we collect from you on the Site, such as your email address, to send you news and newsletters, special offers, and promotions, or to otherwise contact you about our products or information we think may interest you. We also may use the information that we learn about you to assist us in advertising the Tremor Video DSP services to our potential customers on third party websites.
  * To comply with legal obligations, as part of our general business operations, and for other business administration purposes.
  * Where we believe necessary to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person or violations of our privacy policy.

_Non-personally identifiable information_  
Tremor Video DSP generally uses non-personally identifiable information in aggregated form to help measure the Tremor Video DSP Site’s performance and effectiveness, and to improve its features and usefulness.

With whom does Tremor Video DSP share personally identifiable information collected on the Tremor Video DSP Site?

Tremor Video DSP does not share the personally identifiable information that you provide to the Tremor Video DSP Site, other than with its service providers that help Tremor Video DSP provide the services that you request, such as delivery of our email newsletters, and to help Tremor Video DSP manage information provided by job seekers for possible employment with us.

Tremor Video DSP may transfer or assign the information it collects on the Site to any successor-in-interest to Tremor Video DSP (such as a company that acquires Tremor Video DSP), or internally to one or more affiliates (such as a corporate subsidiary, affiliate company, or parent). Tremor Video DSP may also disclose personally identifiable information about a user if it determines that an applicable law, regulation or legal process requires it, or if Tremor Video DSP determines that it needs to share such information to protect or enforce Tremor Video DSP’s rights or the rights of another user.

Does the Tremor Video DSP Site use cookies?

We and our service providers use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Services. We or our service providers may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you.

Cookies. We or our service providers may use cookies to track visitor activity on our Site. A cookie is a text file that a website transfers to your computer’s hard drive for record-keeping purposes. We or our service providers may use cookies to track user activities on our Site, such as the pages visited and time spent on our Site. Most browsers allow users to refuse cookies. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies may not be able to browse certain areas of the Site.

Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, which are embedded invisibly on web pages. We or our service providers may use clear GIFs (also known as web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our Site to track the activities of users of our Site, help us manage content, and compile statistics about usage of our Site. We or our service providers may also use clear GIFs in emails to our users to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed, and track whether our emails are forwarded.

Do-Not-Track. Our Site does not respond to Do Not Track signals. To opt out of Tremor Video DSP’s cookie used for interest-based advertising by clicking on the “Opt Out” button at the top of this page. For more information about Do Not Track signals, please visit [www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

What else should I know about privacy?

_Security_

Tremor Video DSP maintains safeguards to protect the security, integrity and privacy of the personally identifiable information within our reasonable control.  However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to protect your information, please be advised that Tremor Video DSP assumes no responsibility or liability for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third-party access, or other causes beyond Tremor Video DSP’s reasonable control.

_Links to  other websites_

Tremor Video DSP does not control the data collection policies of any third party website linked to the Tremor Video DSP Site. If you click on a link or an advertisement, the privacy policy of the website to which you link will govern the collection and use of your information by that website’s operators. Tremor Video DSP assumes no responsibility or liability for the actions of such third parties with respect to their use of your information or otherwise.

_Collection of  information from minors_

The Tremor Video DSP Site is directed to, and intended for use by, adults only. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen, we will delete such information from our records.

ACCEPTANCE OF PRIVACY POLICY FOR THE TREMOR VIDEO DSP SITE

When you use the Tremor Video DSP Site, you are accepting the terms and conditions of this privacy policy, and Tremor Video DSP will have the right to use your information as described in this privacy policy. If you do not agree to have your information used in any of the ways described in this privacy policy, you must discontinue use of the Tremor Video DSP Site.

We collect information about your activities on certain websites to send you targeted ads. To opt out of targeted advertisements delivered through the Tremor Video DSP services, [click here](http://tremorvideodsp.com/privacy-policy.html).

ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Tremor Video DSP, Inc., a Taptica Company, reserves the right to revise this privacy policy from time to time. We will post any changes, including any material changes, to this privacy policy on our Site. If you have questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please email us at privacy@tremorvideodsp.com or write to us at Tremor Video DSP, Inc., a Taptica Company, Attention: Privacy, 1501 Broadway, New York, NY 10036.

_US Self-regulatory program for online behavioral advertising_

Tremor Video DSP, Inc., a Taptica Company, follows the Digital Advertising Alliance industry privacy standards for online behavioral advertising. To learn more about the program and its principles, [visit the Digital Advertising Alliance](https://www.aboutads.info/).

_Third-party ad service providers_

The following third-party ad service providers may use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies in connection with advertisements delivered by Tremor Video DSP. Click on the links below to find out more about their practices and the choices they provide to you:
